Henry A. Kissinger Papers, Part III: Guide to the Yale University Library Collection
Manuscripts and Archives
- Photographs, 1938 - 2009; Series VII
  - General
    - Bush, George W. with David and Sam Kissinger at White House-photocopies, 2002 November (Box 225, Folder 13)
    - MT&R International Councillors Meeting in Beijing, China with Nancy Kissinger, 2002 November 4-7 (Box 225, Folder 14)
    - Karzai, Hamid and Rania, Queen of Jordan, with Kissinger at International Rescue Committee (IRC) Freedom Award Dinner [includes correspondence], 2002 November 13 (Box 225, Folder 15)
    - 9/11 Commission appointment at the White House, 2002 November 27 (Box 225, Folder 16)
    - Boys and Girls Club luncheon honoring Rudolph W. Giuliani [includes correspondence], 2002 December (Box 225, Folder 17)
    - Chinese People's Institute of Foreign Affairs (CPIFA) trip to China [includes correspondence], 2002 December 2-4 (Box 225, Folder 18)
    - Ford, Gerald R. napping with Crisis, Circa 2003 (Box 225, Folder 19)
    - William and Mary Charter Day with Kofi Annan [includes correspondence], 2003 February 8 (Box 225, Folder 20)
    - Roy, J. Stapleton with Kissinger in China, 2003 March (Box 225, Folder 21)
    - German Historical Institute and Egon Bahr birthday event [includes correspondence], 2003 March 18 (Box 225, Folder 22)
    - Kissinger visit to Cathedral High School, New York, 2003 April 24 (Box 225, Folder 23)
    - Bank Austria Creditanstalt Forum on Europe, Vienna, 2003 June 11 (Box 225, Folder 24)
    - Aden, Robert and family with Kissinger, 2003 June 17, undated (Box 225, Folder 25)
    - Isaacson, Walter, Marvin L. Kalb, Klaus Larres, James R. Schlesinger, Joseph J. Sisco, and Kissinger at John Kluge Center at the Library of Congress, 2003 June 18 (Box 225, Folder 26)
    - International Olympic Committee (IOC) meeting, Prague, 2003 July 2-4 (Box 225, Folder 27)
    - Mandalay Camp, Bohemian Grove, 2003 July 17-20 (Box 225, Folder 28)
    - Henry and Nancy Kissinger with Abigail (dog) at Kent Volunteer Fire Department fair [includes correspondence], 2003 August 23 (Box 225, Folder 29)
    - Russia trip, 2003 September 10-17 (Box 226, Folder 1)
    - Zhang, Yan with Kissinger at the New York office, 2003 September 24 (Box 226, Folder 2)
    - Ferrero-Waldner, Benita speaking with Kissinger [includes correspondence], 2003 September 26 (Box 226, Folder 3)
    - Pan, Jie and Fan Zhu Hua Pan of the Hangzhou Museum with Kissinger in New York, 2003 October 23 (Box 226, Folder 4)
    - Bush, George with Kissinger at George H. W. Bush Presidential Library and Museum, 2003 November 5 (Box 226, Folder 5)
    - Roy, J. Stapleton and Bill Harrison with Kissinger in China, 2003 November 8-14 (Box 226, Folder 6)
    - American Bankers Association (ABA) luncheon [includes correspondence], 2003 December 8 (Box 226, Folder 7)
    - Mehta, Sunil with Kissinger at lunch, 2004 (Box 226, Folder 8)
    - Olympic Games, Athens [1 of 2], 2004 (Box 226, Folder 9)
    - Olympic Games, Athens [2 of 2], 2004 (Box 226, Folder 10)
    - International Bertelsmann Forum, Berlin [includes correspondence], 2004 January 9 (Box 226, Folder 11)
    - Kissinger with unidentified man, 2004 January 20 (Box 226, Folder 12)
    - Kissinger at Princeton University, 2004 February (Box 226, Folder 13)
    - Sino-U.S. Unofficial High Level Dialogue group, 2004 June (Box 226, Folder 14)
    - Kurz, Evi and Walter with Kissinger in Fürth [includes correspondence], 2004 June 7 (Box 226, Folder 15)
    - Edward S. Harkness Eye Institute event, 2004 July 8 (Box 226, Folder 16)
    - Horne, Alistair and Michael Korda with Kissinger in Kent, 2004 August (Box 226, Folder 17)
    - American Express board of directors, 2004 September (Box 226, Folder 18)
    - Park, Jin with Kissinger, 2004 September 2 (Box 226, Folder 19)
    - Alemán, Christiane and Miguel with Kissinger at Mexican Business Summit, 2004 September 19 (Box 226, Folder 20)
    - Bloomberg, Michael with Kissinger at reception honoring Phoenix House, Gracie Mansion, 2004 October 26 (Box 226, Folder 21)
    - Berlusconi, Silvio and Kissinger, 2004 November (Box 226, Folder 22)
    - Bertelsmann Foundation visit in Brussels, 2005 (Box 226, Folder 23)
    - China trip, Peking University, 2005 (Box 226, Folder 24)
    - International Olympic Committee (IOC) meeting, Singapore [includes correspondence], 2005 (Box 226, Folder 25)
    - Rose, Charlie with Kissinger at 92nd Street Y, 2005 (Box 226, Folder 26)
    - Russian children from Vladimir Spivakov International Charity Foundation with Kissinger, Moscow, 2005 (Box 229, Folder 8)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur and another with Kissinger at Marine Corps Scholarship Foundation lunch [includes correspondence], 2005 (Box 226, Folder 27)
    - Trip to Fürth-photocopies, 2005 (Box 226, Folder 28)
    - Anand Panyarachun with Kissinger at Kenan Institute Asia event, 2005 February 18 (Box 226, Folder 29)
    - Guth, Wilfried with Kissinger in Darmstadt, Germany [includes correspondence], 2005 May (Box 227, Folder 1)
    - Kissinger, Henry and Nancy at celebration of 40 years of German-Israeli diplomatic relations [includes correspondence], 2005 May 31 (Box 227, Folder 2)
    - Jewish Community Relations Council (JCRC) event honoring Roger Ailes [includes correspondence], 2005 June 9 (Box 227, Folder 3)
    - Havel, Václav with Kissinger in Prague, 2005 September (Box 227, Folder 4)
    - Kissinger visiting New York Yankees clubhouse, 2005 September 7 (Box 227, Folder 5)
    - Cheney, Dick meeting with Kissinger at the White House, 2005 September 23 (Box 227, Folder 6)
    - Business Council for International Understanding (BCIU) opera gala and award dinner honoring John Browne [includes correspondence], 2005 November (Box 227, Folder 7)
    - Members of the United States Women's Olympic Soccer Team and Paul Fribourg with Kissinger [includes correspondence], 2005 November 30 (Box 227, Folder 8)
    - Brademas, John with Kissinger, 2006 (Box 227, Folder 9)
    - Global Policy Council, 2006 (Box 227, Folder 10)
    - Kissinger participating in "Future of Europe" panel [includes correspondence], 2006 (Box 227, Folder 11)
    - Mandalay Camp, Bohemian Grove, 2006 (Box 227, Folder 12)
    - McLarty, Thomas F. with Kissinger at William J. Clinton Presidential Library and Museum, 2006 (Box 227, Folder 13)
    - De Rothschild, Lynn with Kissinger, 2006 February 20 (Box 227, Folder 14)
    - Alemán, Christiane and Miguel with Henry and Nancy Kissinger at lunch at Le Grenouille, New York, 2006 March 30 (Box 227, Folder 15)
    - Baker Institute for Public Policy event, New York, 2006 April 12 (Box 227, Folder 16)
    - Woodrow Wilson Award for Public Service event, New York, 2006 April 27 (Box 227, Folder 17)
    - Scholl, Hermann with Henry and Nancy Kissinger in Hatvan, Hungary and Kent, 2006 May (Box 227, Folder 18)
    - Israeli Independence Day reception at Israeli Consulate [includes correspondence], 2006 May 3 (Box 227, Folder 19)
    - Merkel, Angela with Kissinger in Germany [includes correspondence], 2006 May 15 (Box 227, Folder 20)
    - Sino-U.S. Unofficial High Level Dialogue, Hoover Institution, 2006 June (Box 227, Folder 21)
    - Cheney, Dick and Kissinger at the White House, 2006 June 19 (Box 227, Folder 22)
    - Die Zeit visit [includes correspondence], 2006 July (Box 227, Folder 23)
    - Benedict XVI with Kissinger in Italy, 2006 September (Box 227, Folder 24)
    - Kissinger with unidentified individuals - photographs from Victor Gao, CNOOC Limited, 2006 October (Box 227, Folder 25)
    - National Committee on U.S.-China Relations ringing the opening bell at the New York Stock Exchange, 2009 January 5 (Box 227, Folder 26)
    - Anand Panyarachun and wife Sodsee with Henry and Nancy Kissinger in Thailand, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 27)
    - Baker, James and unidentified Saudi Arabian or Kuwaiti man with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 28)
    - Bhutto, Benazir and Kissinger with group in Pakistan, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 29)
    - Coca Cola corporate meeting, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 30)
    - De Rose, François and Yvonne with Henry and Nancy Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 31)
    - Ertegun, Mica and Nancy Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 32)
    - Former United States secretaries of state, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 33)
    - Fürth soccer team, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 34)
    - Genscher, Hans Dietrich with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 35)
    - George Bush Presidential Library Foundation event, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 36)
    - Gold, Dore with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 37)
    - Guanhua, Qiao visiting Suzhou gardens with Henry and Nancy Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 38)
    - Havel, Václav with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 39)
    - Interview in Acapulco, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 40)
    - Juan Carlos I, King of Spain, with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 41)
    - Kissinger at black tie event, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 42)
    - Kissinger at dinner with others, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 43)
    - Kissinger at podium, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 44)
    - Kissinger at soccer stadium in Germany, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 45)
    - Kissinger in China, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 46)
    - Kissinger, Nancy and Henry at black tie affair, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 47)
    - Kissinger portrait by Michael Collopy for Architects of Peace, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 48)
    - Kissinger seated on sofa with others, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 49)
    - Kissinger speaking at Foreign Policy Association (FPA), Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 50)
    - Kissinger speaking at Georgetown University, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 51)
    - Kissinger visiting Teach for America classroom, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 52)
    - Kissinger with others at Forstmann Little Conference, Aspen, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 227, Folder 53)
    - Lacroze de Fortabat, Amalia with Kissinger [1 of 2], Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 1)
    - Lacroze de Fortabat, Amalia with Kissinger [2 of 2], Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 2)
    - Lon Nol with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 3)
    - Merkel, Angela with Kissinger at dinner, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 4)
    - Morita, Akio with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 5)
    - Peres, Shimon and Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 6)
    - Phelps de Cisneros, Patricia and others with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 7)
    - Rice, Condoleezza, George Shultz, and Kissinger with others, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 8)
    - Schmidt, Helmut and others with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 9)
    - Seitz, Raymond and others with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 10)
    - Seitz, Raymond with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 11)
    - Takeshita, Noboru with Kissinger in Japan, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 12)
    - Thatcher, Margaret with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 13)
    - Tlatelolco Conference, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 14)
    - Weizsäcker, Richard von with Kissinger, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 15)
    - West Papua, Undated, circa 1967-circa 2009 (Box 228, Folder 16)
  - Rodman (Peter W.) files
    - Paris peace negotiations, 1973 January (Box 228, Folder 17)
    - China, 1973 February (Box 228, Folder 18)
    - Hanoi and Bangkok, 1973 February (Box 228, Folder 19)
    - Hanoi, Peking, and Hong Kong, 1973 February (Box 228, Folder 20)
    - Lima, 1973 February 18 (Box 228, Folder 21)
    - Zavidovo, 1973 May (Box 228, Folder 22)
    - Mexico City, San Clemente, and Washington, DC, 1973 August-September (Box 228, Folder 23)
    - Moscow, 1973 October 21-22 (Box 228, Folder 24)
    - Middle East, 1973 December (Box 228, Folder 25)
    - Geneva, 1973 December 20-21 (Box 228, Folder 26)
    - China, Circa 1974-circa 1979 (Box 228, Folder 27)
    - Damascus, Syria, 1974 May 24 (Box 228, Folder 28)
    - Home from Middle East shuttle, 1974 May 30 (Box 228, Folder 29)
    - China, 1974 November (Box 228, Folder 30)
    - Vladivostok, 1974 November 23 (Box 228, Folder 31)
    - Tel Aviv and Heathrow, 1975 March (Box 228, Folder 32)
    - Jerusalem, 1975 August (Box 228, Folder 33)
    - China, 1975 October (Box 228, Folder 34)
    - Ford, Gerald R. and Anwar Sadat, 1975 October (Box 228, Folder 35)
    - China presidential trip, 1975 December (Box 228, Folder 36)
    - China, 1979 April (Box 228, Folder 37)
  - Albums
    - Paris peace negotiations, 1972 - 1973 (Box 230)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 1, 1973 September-1973 December (Box 231)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 2, 1973 December-1974 February (Box 232)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 3, 1974 March-1974 June (Box 233)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 4, 1974 July (Box 234)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 5, 1974 October-November (Box 235)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 6, 1974 November-1975 March (Box 236)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 7, 1975 May-August (Box 237)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 8, 1975 August-1976 February (Box 238)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 9, 1976 April-August (Box 239)
    - State Department photographs, Volume 10, 1976 September-December (Box 240)
    - Brazil, 1974 February (Box 241)
    - South Korea, 1974 November 22 (Box 242)
    - China [1 of 2], 1974 November 25-28 (Box 243)
    - China [2 of 2], 1974 November 25-28 (Box 244)
    - Helsinki, 1975 July-August (Box 245)
    - Indonesia, 1975 December 5-6 (Box 246)
    - Moscow, 1976 January 22-23 (Box 247)
    - Peru, 1976 February (Box 248)
    - Columbia, 1976 February 22-23 (Box 249)
    - Zaire [1 of 2], 1976 April (Box 250)
    - Zaire [2 of 2], 1976 April (Box 251)
    - Félix Houphouët-Boigny Peace Prize award ceremony, Paris, 1994 July 6 (Box 252)
    - Seoul Economic Forum, 1999 (Box 253)
- Moving Images and Sound Recordings, 1976 - 1997; Series VIII
  Series VIII is arranged into two subseries: Video recordings and Sound recordings.
  The video and sound recordings document a small number of speaking engagements and interviews in which Kissinger participated, primarily from the late 1980s to the early 2000s and many of them overseas.
  A similar collection of video and sound recordings, mostly dating from the earlier period of 1961 to 1985, can be found in Part II of the Henry A. Kissinger papers.
  - Video recordings
    - Charles de Gaulle documentary interview, Circa 1987; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 254)
    - New York City promotional commercial, miscellaneous television excerpts, and George W. Bush-Albert Gore presidential debate, Circa 1987-circa 1998; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 255)
    - Freeport-McMoRan interview, Indonesian television (longer version), Circa 1987-circa 1998; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 256)
    - Freeport-McMoRan interview, Indonesian television (shorter version), Circa 1987-circa 1998; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 257)
    - HOBY Awards tribute, Circa 1987-circa 1998; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 258)
    - NHK New Years interview, Japan, 1987 December 14; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 259)
    - Distinguished Public Service Medal award ceremony for Cyrus Vance, Center for the Study of the Presidency, 1988 March 10; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 260)
    - Signature of agreements between Gorbachev Foundation and Fundacion Colloquium, Circa 1991-circa 1998; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 261)
    - Gas Mart '92 general session with keynote address by Ross Perot, Opryland Hotel, Nashville, Tennessee, 1992 April 14; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 262)
    - Philip Morris Foundation, Munich, Germany, 1992 June 30; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 263)
    - "U.S. Leadership: The Use and Abuse of Multilateralism" by Jeane Kirkpatrick and "What Is U.S. Foreign Policy Strategy" by Kissinger, Republican National Committee Foreign Policy Forum, 1994 July 27; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 264)
    - Bayerisches Fernsehen interview, Circa 1995; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 265)
    - First Annual B. C. Lee Lecture, 1995 February 1; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 266)
    - Homenaje Argentino a Personalidades Internacionales, 1995 April; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 267)
    - Interview in Mexico, 1996 February 12; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 268)
    - United States Army War College address, Bliss Hall (copy 1), 1996 May 2; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 269)
    - United States Army War College address, Bliss Hall (copy 2), 1996 May 2; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 270)
    - Ulusal KalDer Kongresi speech, Turkey, 1996 November 13; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 271)
    - Cavuto on Business television interview, 1996 November 23; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 272)
    - Yanglan Horizon interview, 1997 February 5; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 273)
    - Greater New York Hospital Association tribute to Paul Marks, 1997 May 28; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 274)
    - Prix Félix Houphouët-Boigny pour la Recherche de la Paix 1996, 1997 June 26; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 275)
    - Republic National Bank of New York, Monaco, 1997 July 2; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 276)
    - Am Ende des Jahrhunderts Helmut Schmidt im Gespräch mit Henry Kissinger, 1998 April 24; 1 videocassette (vhs) (Box 277)
    - "Worry from Far Away," a special film recorded by Zhejiang Satellite Television for the exhibition hosted by the Hangzhou Sino-U.S. Friendship Civilian Memorial Hall to celebrate the birthday of Kissinger (English edition), 2003 May (Box 277A)
    - "Worry from Far Away," a special film recorded by Zhejiang Satellite Television for the exhibition hosted by the Hangzhou Sino-U.S. Friendship Civilian Memorial Hall to celebrate the birthday of Kissinger (Chinese edition), 2003 May (Box 277B)
  - Sound recordings
    - Mignon C. Smith, "Uranium/support for private funding," ALANET, 1976 February 17; 1 audiocassette (Box 278)
    - Remarks by Paulo D. Villares and Kissinger during dinner, Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1987 June 23; 1 audiocassette (Box 279)
    - United Cerebral Palsey, New York Hilton, 1992 December 15; 1 audiocassette (Box 280)
    - Council of Jewish Federations General Assembly, Boston, 1995 November 16; 1 audiocassette (Box 281)
    - Rabin lecture on United States and Middle East policy, 1997 November 9; 1 audiocassette (Box 282)
    - Bryce Harlow Oral History Project interview, 2005 December 5 (Box 283)
- Additional material, 2011; Accession 2014-M-66
  The files contain memoranda of conversation, correspondence, and notes concerning Kissinger's meetings with Chinese officials in 2011 about China's economic and foreign policies.
  - Meetings with Chinese [1 of 3], 2011 (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - Meetings with Chinese [2 of 3], 2011 (Box 1a, Folder 2)
  - Meetings with Chinese [3 of 3], 2011 (Box 1a, Folder 3)